You're Going to Learn... Even if it Kills You.
The Lesson is a drama, thriller, horror film directed by Ruth Platt.
Two schoolboy delinquents learn a lesson that they will never forget when a
teacher at the end of his tether decides to abduct them.
Mr Gale, played by Robert Hands.
Fin, played by Evan Bendall.
Mia, played by Michaela Prchalová.
Tanja, played by Dolya Gavanski.
Jake, played by Tom Cox.
Joel, played by Rory Coltart.
The Piano Lesson is a 2024 American drama film directed by Malcolm
Washington, who co-wrote the screenplay with Virgil Williams.
It is an adaptation of the 1987 Pulitzer Prize-winning play by August Wilson.
It stars an ensemble cast of Samuel L.
Jackson, John David Washington, Ray Fisher, Michael Potts, Erykah Badu,
Skylar Aleece Smith, Danielle Deadwyler, and Corey Hawkins.
The Piano Lesson premiered at the 51st Telluride Film Festival on August 31, 2024, and it was released in select
theaters in the United States on November 8, 2024, before streaming on Netflix on November 22.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics.
Deadwyler was lauded for her performance, earning nominations for the Critics' Choice
Award and the Screen Actors Guild Award for Best Supporting Actress.
The tone is dark and emotional and intense.